Guide to the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific records
1888-2019
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6144
Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific
10.82 cubic feet 13 boxes
0.425 GB 3 CDs
Materials related to the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union
The Deep Sea Fishermen's Union (DSFU) was established in November 1912 to represent the interests of fishermen, many of whom worked aboard boats owned by others. Fishing was and continues to be a very dangerous occupation. Workers formed unions to help mitigate the risks of this dangerous occupation and to ensure that they were paid fairly by the vessel owners.
The union represents long-line fishermen- those who use fishing lines and hooks to obtain their catch as opposed to dragging nets behind a vessel. Over the course of its history, the DSFU has been active in the management of halibut fisheries, and were among the groups that helped to establish the International Pacific Halibut Commission in the 1920s. The union has advocated for and helped establish programs of conservation and fleet management through government and self-regulation. In the wake of the establishment of a 200-mile offshore fishing limit in 1976, the DSFU continues to be active in that process of fishing and conservation. Because of this model, the union has evolved to an organization that is not only the collective bargaining agent of workers in relation to ship owners, but a body that lobbies for legislation and policies that are in the interest of its members.
The Deep Sea Fishermen's Union records span the years 1888-2019 and include financial records, meeting minutes, correspondence, collective bargaining records, membership records, administrative files, subject files on issues facing the union and its members, photographs, and several artifacts. Records also include materials collected for the publication of the book "One Hook at a Time," a history of the union published in 2014. For more detailed information about the materials in each accession, please consult the arrangement and scope and content notes at the accession level of the finding aid.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Organized into 2 accessions.
Accession No. 6144-001, Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific records, 1888-2017
Accession No. 6144-002, Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific records, 1890-2019
No restrictions on access. No user access copy is currently available for the 3 CDs in 6144-002. Arrangements can be made to preview the media onsite in the Special Collections Reading Room by contacting Special Collections well in advance of your visit.
Gift of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, 2017-2019
Centennial history book "One Hook at a Time" was removed from the collection and added to the Special Collections non-circulating collection. Access information is viewable in the library catalog record for this item.
Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific$vArchives; Labor unions$zUnited States; Labor$zUnited States; Labor movement$zUnited States; Minutes (Records); Ephemera; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Fisheries and Wildlife
- Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific records, 1888-2017; 6144-001; 4.33 cubic feet (6 boxes)
  The 001 accession of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union records span the years 1888-2017 and contain financial records, meeting minutes, correspondence, collective bargaining records, administrative files, an artifact, and subject files on issues facing the union and its members. The records also include materials collected for the publication of the book "One Hook at a Time," a history of the union published in 2014. Records include those of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association, which holds title to the organization's Ballard Avenue union hall purchased in January 1948.
  The records in the 001 accession are arranged into the following eight series based on generating body, function, or format:
  SERIES 1: FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1949-1996
  SERIES 2: ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1947-2014
  SERIES 3: MINUTES, 1932-1983
  SERIES 4: CORRESPONDENCE, 1956-1998
  SERIES 5: COLLECTIVE BARGAINING RECORDS, 1925-1984
  SERIES 6: SUBJECT FILES 1936-2012
  SERIES 7: PUBLICATION RECORDS, 1888-2014
  SERIES 8: ARTIFACTS, 2017
  No restrictions on access.
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1949-1996; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 1/1-2/10)
    - General ledger, 1956 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - General ledger, 1957 (Box-folder ½)
    - General ledger, 1958 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - General ledger, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - General ledger, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - General ledger, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - General ledger, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - General ledger, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - General ledger, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - General ledger, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - General ledger, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - General fund check register, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Receipts summary, 1956-1970 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Mortuary fund, 1956-1965 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Halibut Lay-up fund, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association ledger, 1949-1966 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Payroll records, 1949-1952 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Payroll records, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Pension account, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Rental deposits, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Halibut lay-up fund payments by vessel, 1957-1986 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1947-2014; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 4/1-4/5)
    - Constitution and Bylaws Committee, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Articles of incorporation, Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association, 1947 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Jeff Kahrs. "One Hook at a Time: A History of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific", 2014 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Personnel, 1988-1998 (Box-folder 4/5)
  - MINUTES, 1932-1983; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 3/1-3/2, 4/6-27)
    - Executive Board, 1977-1983 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - All branches, 1932-1935 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - All branches, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Seattle meetings, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Seattle meetings, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Seattle meetings, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Seattle meetings, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Seattle meetings, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Seattle meetings, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Seattle meetings, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Seattle meetings, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Seattle meetings, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Seattle meetings, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Astoria branch, 1938 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Juneau branch, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Juneau branch, 1942-1953 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Ketchikan branch, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Ketchikan branch, 1942-1953 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Petersburg branch, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Petersburg branch, 1943-1952 (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Prince Rupert branch, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Prince Rupert branch, 1943-1949 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Vancouver, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association minutes, 1948-1974 (Box-folder 4/27)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1956-1998; SERIES 4 (Box-folder 4/28-5/4)
    - Affiliation correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 4/28)
    - Dues checkoff, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 4/29)
    - Lay-up program, 1959 (Box-folder 4/30)
    - Mortuary fund, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Schwerin, Burns, Campbell & French, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 4/32)
    - U.S. Senate and House of Representatives, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 4/33)
    - General correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 4/34)
    - General correspondence, 1995 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - General correspondence, 1996 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - General correspondence (part 1 of 2), 1997 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - General correspondence (part 2 of 2), 1997 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - COLLECTIVE BARGAINING RECORDS, 1925-1984; SERIES 5 (Box-folder 5/5-5/10)
    - Agreements, 1925-1959 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Agreements, 1957-1977 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Negotiations, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Agreement negotiation and arbitration, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Set line agreements, 1945-1984 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Set line agreement correspondence, 1956-1973 (Box-folder 5/10)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1936-2012; SERIES 6 (Box-folder 5/11-6/1)
    - Alaska Fishermen's Union, 1956 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Boat and crew roster notebooks, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Claims, 1959 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Halibut lay-up conferences, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Halibut Producers Pool (insurance), 1937-1958 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Heading and gutting specifications, 1936-1958 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Lay-up program -- Kodiak, Alaska, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Mercury problem in halibut, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - National Labor Bureau, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Pacific Coast Fishermen's Union, 1956 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Publicity, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Seattle Fishermen's Exchange, 1937-1960 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Settlement records and delivery poundage, Seattle union vessels, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Tariffs, 1950 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Trade shows, 1995 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Press clippings, 1993 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Press clippings, 2002 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Press clippings, 2003 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Press clippings, 2004 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Press clippings, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 5/30)
    - Press clippings, 2008 (Box-folder 5/31)
    - Press clippings, 2012 (Box-folder 5/32)
    - The International Pacific Halibut Commission. The Pacific halibut: biology, fishery, and management. Technical report No. 12, 1987 (Box-folder 5/33)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission. Annual report, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 5/34)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission. Annual report, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 5/35)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission. Annual report, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 5/36)
    - Audio cassette recording of Bob Alvorson, Lokken, Davies, undated (Box-folder 6/1)
  - PUBLICATION RECORDS, 1888-2014; SERIES 7 (Box-folder 6/2-6/9)
    - Union history book credits (part 1 of 3), undated (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Union history book credits (part 2 of 3), undated (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Union history book credits (part 3 of 3), undated (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Book "One Hook at a Time" draft copy, approximately 2014 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Photo license records, 2013-2014 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Photo use permission records, 2011-2013 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Book "One Hook at a Time " with corrections and notes, approximately 2014 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Historical news accounts of accidents, 1888-2006 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - ARTIFACTS, 2017; SERIES 8 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Union patches, 2017 (Box-folder 3/2)
- Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific records, 1890-2019; 6144-002; 6.49 cubic feet 7 boxes 7 boxes; 0.425 GB 3 CDs
  The 002 accession of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union records contain meeting minutes, membership lists, collective bargaining records, photographs, and agreements with fishing vessel owners as well as correspondence and subject files related to fisheries policy and relationships with other organizations; industry organizing in the 1930s, including Congress of Industrial Organization (CIO) efforts; records of the Halibut Fishermen’s Wives Association; halibut marketing; and the introduction of individual fishing quotas in the halibut fishery. Historical reference files include materials collected for publication of the 100th anniversary book “One Hook at a Time” as well as other historical accounts, and include press clippings, interviews with long-time union members, and secondary works about long-line fishing. Also included are records related to the Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association that holds the title to the DSFU union hall located on Ballard Avenue, including leasing records with the Seattle concert venue, The Tractor Tavern.
  The records in the 002 accession are arranged into the following series and subseries:
  SERIES 1: FINANCIAL RECORDS, 2003-2016
  SERIES 2: ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1947-2017
  Subseries A: Constitution and Bylaws, 1965-2003
  Subseries B: Elections, 1950-2004
  Subseries C: Building Records, 1947-2017
  Subseries D: Administrative Records, 1981-2017
  Subseries E: Membership Records, 1981-2016
  SERIES 3: MINUTES, 1977-2017
  SERIES 4: CORRESPONDENCE, 1952-2007
  SERIES 5: COLLECTIVE BARGAINING RECORDS, 1912-2006
  SERIES 6: SUBJECT FILES, 1942-2007
  SERIES 7: HISTORICAL REFERENCE FILES, 1890-2012
  Subseries A: Interviews, 1985-2015
  Subseries B: Photographs, 1910-2011
  Subseries C: Secondary Accounts, 1940-2012
  Subseries D: Press Clippings, 1890-2019
  SERIES 8: PUBLICATION RECORDS, 1992-2015
  SERIES 9: ARTIFACTS, 1931-2010
  No restrictions on access. No user access copy is currently available for the 3 CDs. Arrangements can be made to preview the media onsite in the Special Collections Reading Room by contacting Special Collections well in advance of your visit.
  Donated by James Johnson of the Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific
  - FINANCIAL RECORDS, 2003-2016; SERIES 1 (Box-folder 1/1-1/4)
    - Lay Up Fund Financial Data, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Building Association Financial Data, 2004 (Box-folder ½)
    - Dues Receipts, 2009-2015 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Financial Reports, 2015-2016 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - ORGANIZATIONAL RECORDS, 1947-2017; SERIES 2 (Box-folder 1/5-1/17)
    - Constitution and Bylaws, 1965-2003; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/5/1/6)
      - Constitution and Bylaws, 2003 (Box-folder 1/5)
      - Draft Revision of Constitution and Bylaws of Deep Sea Fishermen's Union of the Pacific, approximately 1970 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Elections, 1950-2004; Subseries B (Box-folder 1/7-1/8)
      - Union Officer Balloting Reports, 1950-1956, 1963 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Officer Elections, 2004 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Building Records, 1947-2017; Subseries C (Box-folder 1/9-1/10)
      - Deep Sea Fishermen's Union Building Association Bylaws/Lease Agreement 2016, 1947, 2016 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Tractor Tavern Lease Agreement, 2007-2017 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Administrative Records, 1981-2017; Subseries D (Box-folder 1/11-1/12, ½9)
      - Executive Director Job Description, approximately 2008-2017 (Box-folder 1/11)
      - Personnel Contract, Sara Chapman, 2013-2015 (Box-folder 1/12)
      - Office Correspondence and Subject File Backup, 2002-2004 (Box-folder ½9)
    - Membership Records, 1981-2016; Subseries E (Box-folder 1/13-1/17)
      - Membership Directories, 1982-1003 (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Membership List, 1981-2016 (Box-folder 1/14)
      - Membership List by Vessel and Crew Members, 1997-2003 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Member Lists (1 of 2), 2013 (Box-folder 1/16)
      - Member Lists (2 of 2), 2013 (Box-folder 1/17)
  - MINUTES, 1977-2017; SERIES 3 (Box-folder 1/18-1/26)
    - Seattle Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box-folder ½0)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989 (Box-folder ½1)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1990-1992 (Box-folder ½2)
    - Executive Board Minutes, 1984-1994 (Box-folder ½3)
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 (Box-folder ½4)
    - Building Association and Executive Board Minutes, 2016 (Box-folder ½5)
    - Building Association and Executive Board Minutes, 2017 (Box-folder ½6)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1952-2007; SERIES 4 (Box-folder ½7-1/41, 2/1-2/14)
    - General Correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box-folder ½7)
    - Correspondence: L, 1956-1959 (Box-folder ½8)
    - Alaska Fishermen's Union, 1957-1959 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Aquaculture and Fisheries Policy, 2006 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - British Columbia Deep Sea Fishermen's Union, Prince Rupert, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Congressional Correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Exclusive Economic Zone Off Alaska and Washington, 2006 (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Fisheries Imports, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Fishermen and Allied Workers Union Local 30, International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Ketchikan, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Fishermen and Allied Workers Union Local 30, International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, Ketchikan, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Fishing Industry Policy, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Fishing Vessel Owners Association, 1953-1959 (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Fishing Vessel Quest Sale, 2002 (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Halibut Fishermen's Wives Association, 1956-1978 (Box-folder 1/41)
    - Health Care for Fishermen, 2006 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Juneau Agent Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Lay-Up Program - Pelican, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Lay-Up Program - Unalaska, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Legal Services, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act Reauthorization, 2006 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - National Labor Relations Board, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Petersburg Fishermen's Union, Independent, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Sailors' Union of the Pacific Affiliation, 1999 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - United Fishermen and Allied Workers Union (Vancouver, B.C.), 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - United Fishermen and Allied Workers Union (Vancouver, B.C.), 1962-1972 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - United States Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Washington State Department of Fisheries, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Washington State Federation of Labor, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - COLLECTIVE BARGAINING RECORDS, 1912-2006; SERIES 5 (Box-folder 2/15-2/31)
    - Set Line Agreements, 1912, 1919 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Set Line Agreement, 1994 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Set Line Agreement, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Set Line Agreement, 2006 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Organization of Crab Fishermen, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Regina Grievance, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Fishing Vessel Masonic Grievance, 1984 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Fishing Vessel Majestic Grievance, 1986 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Fishing Vessel Polaris Grievance, 1986 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Fishing Vessel Sylvia Grievances, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Fishing Vessel Ocean Harvester Grievance, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Fishing Vessel Republic Grievance, 1982 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Fishing Vessel Kristine Grievance, 1983 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Fishing Vessel Hoover Grievance, 1984 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Fishing Vessel Aleutian Grievances, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Fishing Vessel Vansee Grievance, 1981 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Trial Committee Hearing Records, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 2/31)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1942-2007; SERIES 6 (Box-folder 2/32-2/43, 3/1-3/42, 4/1-4/8)
    - Deep Sea Fishermen's Union Presentations, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - 110th Congress Report on Processor Shares of Individual Fishing Quotas, 2006 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Alaska Seafood Marketing Institute (ASMI) Committee Materials, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Alaska Seafood Marketing Institute Board and Committee Meetings, 2006 (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Aquaculture, 2006 (Box-folder 2/36)
    - British Columbia Halibut and Sablefish Aquaculture, 2001-2006 (Box-folder 2/37)
    - Cod Freezer Longliner Buyout Recommendations, 2006 (Box-folder 2/38)
    - Deep Sea Fishermen's Building Association, 2007 (Box-folder 2/39)
    - Sablefish Marketing, 2005 (Box-folder 2/40)
    - Paint Exterior of Building - Contractor Information, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 2/41)
    - Halibut Charter Guideline Harvest Level Measures - Public Review Draft, 2006 (Box-folder 2/42)
    - Halibut Charter Individual Fishing Quotas, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 2/43)
    - Halibut Charter Individual Fishing Quotas, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Halibut Coalition, 2006 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Halibut Fishermen's Wives' Association, approximately 1965-1975 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Fish Oil Antitrust Case, 1942 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Fisheries Conference Reports, 1972 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Fisheries Policy Issues, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Gulf of Alaska Rationalization, 2006 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Bering Sea Fleet Buyback, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Report of Earnings of Boats and Fishermen in the Seattle Halibut-Blackcod Fleet, approximately 1959 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - List of Alaska halibut Vessels, 1956 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Halibut Liver Oil Production, 1940-1953 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Halibut Industry Promotional Materials, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Halibut Recipes - Press Clippings, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Halibut Recipe Promotional Photographs, 1962 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Stories, Folklore, Songs, approximately 2010 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Otter Trawl Fishermen, 1952-1957 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Fishing Industry Unions in British Columbia, 1950-1989 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Vessel Lay-Up Fund Review Meeting, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Individual Fishing Quotas (IFQ), 1991-1993 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - IFQs: The Responsible Choice, 1993 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Individual Fishing Quota (IFQ) Holders, 1997 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission Reports, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission. "The Pacific Halibut Biology, Fishery, and Management." Technical Report No. 16, 1978 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission (IHPC) Meeting, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission, 2005 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission Annual Meeting, 2006 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - International Pacific Halibut Commission (Brochure), approximately 1990 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Lifeboat Inspection, 1964 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Geneva Law of the Sea Conference, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Resolutions and summary of proceedings. Four nations conference between fishermen's unions of Japan, U.S.S.R., United States and Canada, 1959 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Ron Miller. "Limited Entry in the North Pacific Halibut Fishery" (draft), 1998 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Lay-Up Program, 1955-1956 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Lay-Up Program, 1957 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Lay-Up Program, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Lay-Up Program, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Lay-Up Program, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Lay-Up Program, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 3/38)
    - Marine Stewardship Council Certification, 2006 (Box-folder 3/39)
    - NOAA National Marine Fisheries Service. "Commercial Fishing Crew Demographics of the North Pacific" 1995-2005 Report (draft), 2004 (Box-folder 3/40)
    - North Pacific Fishery Management Council, 2005-2006 (Box-folder 3/41)
    - NOAA National Marine Fisheries Service. Fisheries Utilization Comments, 2014 (Box-folder 3/42)
    - North Pacific Fishery Management Council Action Memos, 2016 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Pacific Fishery Management Council, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Seattle Fishermen's Exchange, 1947-2000 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Seattle Fishermen's Terminal, 2001 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Ad hoc Surveillance Committee, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Note on Tuna Conference, 1970 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Vessel Lists, 1998-2004 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Office Notes, 2006 (Box-folder 4/8)
  - HISTORICAL REFERENCE FILES, 1890-2012; SERIES 7 (Box-folder 4/9-4/53, 5/1-5/41, 6/1-6/3)
    - Interviews, 1985-2015; Subseries A (Box-folder 4/9-4/13)
      - Transcript from Interview with Jimmy Clark, approximately 1992 (Box-folder 4/9)